犯罪心理
第八季  第十三集
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
尼克白盼Summer  紫玉
翻
译
油炸电风扇  和子
翻译  芒果妖怪  爱卿遛小鸟
坏D小泡  宁馨儿
翻
译
时间轴  菜六水  贝贝
校对  坏D小泡
特效&后期  灰灰是菇凉
精校&总监  坏D小泡
杰作
Magnum Opus
《犯罪心理》前情提要
Previously on "Criminal Minds"...
你觉得他知道我们的事了吗
Do you think he knows about us?
据我所知他还不知道
As far as I can tell he doesn't.
那下周日再聊
Well, guess I'll talk to you next Sunday.
再会  爱你
Bye. Love you.
我得告诉你一些事情
I need to tell you something.
梅芙失踪了  我觉得是被跟踪狂抓住了
Maeve is missing. I think her stalker has her.
请帮帮我
Please help me.
帮我找到她
Help me find her.
和内容无关
See, it's not about the message.
而是颜料  他在她脸上画的颜料
It's about the medium. What he used to draw on her face.
这是黑色眼线液
It's black eyeliner.
跟踪狂是个女人
The stalker's a woman.
打扰一下  博士
Excuse me, doctor.
我想我知道嫌犯是谁了
I think I know who the unsub is.
你从哪拿的梅芙的衣服
Where did you get Maeve's clothes?
从她衣柜里拿的
From her closet.
就在我打伤她的头之后
Right after I bashed her head in.
站上去
Get on the ledge.
如果你想杀了我  就动手吧
If you're gonna kill me, you kill me,
我是不会跳的
but I am not jumping.
斯宾塞另有想法
Spencer has a different idea.
卸下武器  脱掉防弹背心  独自进来
Take your gun and vest off and come in alone.
让我替她
Let me take her place.
你愿意为了她牺牲自己
You would kill yourself for her?
是
Yes.
不要
Wait!
丹妮尔  我是凯莉
Danielle, it's Kelly--again.
你在哪  我邀你晚上一起来跳舞的时候
Where are you? When I said let's go out dancing tonight,
可没想让你把我一个人扔在这里
I didn't expect it to involve you leaving me alone
自己去勾搭兄弟会的人
while you scam on some frat guy.
十分钟内给我回电话  不然我就走了
Call me. You've got 10 minutes, then I'm out of here.
有人吗
Hello?
亲爱的
Hey, baby.
工作怎么样
How was work?
狗屁工作  小费太少了
It sucked. Tips were horrible.
我觉得应该在上班路上来看看斯宾塞
Thought I'd check on Spence on my way into work.
对  我也是
Yeah. Me, too.
都是你准备的吗
Are these all from you?
是啊
Maybe.
那个里面是什么
What's in that one?
有坚果和种子
Mixed nuts and seeds.
我一直在想有什么东西能让他感觉好一些
I'm trying to think of something that will help him feel better.
于是我就像里德那样  做了一大堆研究
So I went Reid-like and I did a bunch of research
最后查到  坚果和种子
and it turns out that nuts and seeds
具有天然的镁元素
have naturally occurring magnesium,
镁元素能促进产生血清素
and magnesium influences the production of serotonin,
而血清素会使大脑产生非常非常欢快的感觉
which is a happy happy joy joy chemical in the brain.
不知道真的假的
I don't know.
斯宾塞  听着  你在屋里吧
Spence, listen, if you're in there,
我们只是想知道你没事
we just want to know that you're all right.
如果你还清醒的话  敲两下门
Knock twice if you're conscious.
他还能恢复正常吗
Is he ever gonna be ok?
早晚会的
Eventually.
他也知道  不管如何
And he knows we're all here for him,
他还有我们
no matter what.
她说的没错
Yeah. What she said.
走吧
Come on.
好
Ok.
《约翰・史密斯的告白》
你好  我是斯宾塞・里德  请留言
Hello. This is Spencer Reid. Please leave a message.
里德  又是我
Hey, Reid, it's me. Again.
开会了
Hey, we're gathering.
我这就来
All right, I'm coming.
听着  孩子  回头给我个电话
Now, listen, kid, uh, give me a call when you can.
是他吗
Was that him?
语音信箱
Voicemail.
已经两周了
It's been two weeks.
你还好吗
You ok?
还好
Yeah.
我不好
Well, no.
有时我在想
Sometimes I wonder if I hadn't
如果我不催他和梅芙见面的话
pushed him so hard to meet maeve...
布莱克  你不能责备自己鼓励他
Blake, you can't blame yourself for encouraging him.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
有些事不管怎样都会发生的
It was bound to happen no matter what.
我真想念里德
I miss Reid.
他告诉你要休息多久吗
Did he tell you how long?
没有  我跟他说需要歇多久就歇多久
No. I told him to take as much time as he needed.
至少我还有个机会和卡洛琳说再见
At least I got a chance to say good-bye to Carolyn.
我真不敢想象
I can't imagine--
女士们先生们  我们要去金州了[加州]
Ladies and gents, the Golden State awaits.
他生前叫加里・波特
Meet who was formerly Gary Porter.
昨晚被发现陈尸于旧金山夜总会外
He was found dead outside a San Francisco night club last night.
以及帕梅拉・赫德
And Pamela Hurd--
她的尸体于旧金山教会区
she was found near a cable car stop
电缆车站附近被发现
in San Francisco's Mission District.
他们的尸体都用透明塑料包住了
They were both found wrapped in clear plastic.
资料显示他们死于被发现几小时
It says here they were dead only a few hours before they were found.
时间这么短  化学元素
That's not long enough for the elements
不可能让尸体变这么白
to have made them that pale.
因为我们马上就要进入
'Cause that's where we enter
诡异镇  恶心巷了
the town of weirdville on the corner of eew and icky-icky.
两名死者的血液几乎都被抽光了
Both victims were almost completely drained of their blood.
只剩下不到一品脱[约551毫升]
Less than a pint left.
凶手抽了他们的血
He's exsanguinating them.
是趁他们还活着的时候
While they were still alive.
这样可能方便些
It might be utilitarian.
他不着急杀他们  好让血液自行泵出来
He needs them alive so they can pump out the blood themselves.
把人体内的血抽得那么彻底  这很难做到
Draining a body like that is extremely hard to do.
一旦心脏停止跳动
Once the heart stops pumping,
想再抽血就很难了
it's difficult to continue to extract the blood.
所以问题就是  他是怎么做的
So the question is, how is he doing it?
我真希望你没问这个问题
Oh, I wish you wouldn't have asked that
因为我要给你们看这些图片了
'cause now I gotta show this picture.
两名死者的股动脉处都有很大的孔
There are large bore holes in the femoral artery of each victim.
看来我们的不明嫌犯还挺懂医
Our unsub could have medical knowledge.
很有可能
It's possible.
我们去现场搜集更多信息
We'll know more when we get there.
30分钟后起飞
Wheels up in 30.
我只剩下鲜血  尽管拿去
"My blood alone remains. Take it.
但别让我受罪太久
But do not make me suffer long."
玛丽・安托瓦内特
Marie antoinette.
[早年为奥地利女大公  后为法国王后]
为什么选这两个人
Why these two victims?
他们的社会地位  种族和性别均不同
He's crossed socioeconomic, race, and gender lines.
40多岁的白人男性
One white males in his 40s,
一个富有的对冲基金经理
a wealthy hedge fund manager.
和一名黑人女性
And an African American female,
刚进入旧金山州立大学
just started college at San Francisco State,
身兼数职以维持生计
worked several jobs just to get by.
为什么要抽血呢
Yeah, but why drain the blood?
他是在折磨死者吗
Is he doing it to torture the victims?
还是单纯的为了血
Or is it about the blood?
可能是种心理上的折磨
Might be a form of psychological torture.
虽然被害人可能不怎么痛苦
While not necessarily painful,
但抽血确实需要时间
exsanguination does take time.
可能是迷恋血液或者抽血
It could be a fetish for the blood and the bloodletting.
说不定
What about...
是饮血
drinking it?
弗里兹・哈曼  汉诺威吸血鬼
Fritz Haarmann, the vampire of Hanover,
他杀死的人大多喉咙直接被咬开
killed many of his victims by biting through their throats.
这个不明嫌犯用管子之类的设备
This unsub used some sort of tubing device
从股动脉抽血
to drain the blood from the femoral arteries.
伤口处没有唾液
There isn't any saliva on the wound.
没有被咬的痕迹
Just because there's no bite marks
不代表能排除吸血鬼式作案
doesn't mean we should rule out vampirism.
坏消息  罪案斗士们
Bad news, crime-fighters.
警察又在公园长椅上发现了一具
Police just found another body wrapped in plastic
用塑料包起来的尸体  血也被抽干了
on a park bench, drained of blood.
我想附近应该没有两个变态
I'm gonna assume there's not two creeps
干着一样的事吧
in the area doing the same thing?
加西亚  请你通知旧金山警局
Garcia, will you tell San Francisco P.D.
我们马上去犯罪现场
we'll meet them at the crime scene?
没问题
Consider them told.
戴夫  你和布莱克去犯罪现场见警探
Dave, you and Blake meet the detectives at the crime scene.
摩根  你去法医那看看
Morgan, go see the medical examiner,
小洁和我在警局行动
and JJ and I will set up at the police station.
我们去跟死者家属谈谈
We'll talk to the families,
看能否找到两人之间的联系
see if we can find a connection.
警探
Detective.
我是特别督察探员罗西
SSA Rossi.
这位是特别督察探员布莱克
This is SSA Blake.
我是莱尼・迈尔斯警探
Detective Lenny Miles.
你们能来真是太好了
It's great to have you guys here.
死者名叫林恩・斯蒂文斯
So the victim's name is Lynn Stevens.
她也像前两名死者一样  被抽干了血
She's drained, just like the last two,
但她身上有点新花样
but there's something new.
新花样
New?
他把她眼睑割了
He's removed her eyelids.
我都不想猜
I don't even want to take a guess
为什么会有人这么做
as to why someone would do that.
眼部周围有大量血液
There's excessive blood around the eyes.
他是在她死之前割的
He did this antemortem.
他的虐待兴致开始升级了
His sadism is evolving.
他的折磨这次肯定
And his torture is definitely
不止是心理上的了
more than psychological at this point.
我真不明白怎么会有人做出这种事
I just don't understand why someone would do this.
还是很难以置信
It's all still so hard to believe.
我就问几个关于你丈夫的问题
I just need to ask you a few questions about your husband.
帕米是个好女孩
Pammy was a great girl. You know?
真的很友善
Really friendly.
她和大家都处得很好
She loved everyone, and everyone loved her.
她被人绑架那晚
And you two had worked together
你俩在一起工作吗
the night that she was abducted?
他给我打过电话
He called me.
他说他在下班回家的路上了
He said he was on his way home from work.
只要中途去完成一笔交易就行
He just needed to stop off and close up a deal.
他行程里写着那晚没事
He didn't have anything in his schedule for that night.
你知道是什么交易吗
Do you have any idea what that deal was?
下班后  她说一直很喜欢长距离散步
After work, she said she always liked to go on long walks.
她一直喋喋不休说这里的建筑风格
She was always going on about the architecture,
跟俄勒冈州完全不同
how it's nothing like Oregon.
她刚搬来旧金山吗
She had just moved to San Francisco?
你还知道她有什么朋友
Are there any other friends of hers that you know
我们需要找来问话的吗
who we should talk to?
她半工半读
She was paying her way through school.
不在这里  就是在打另一份工
When she wasn't there, she was always at another job.
勉强生存而已
Just trying to stay afloat. You know?
如果你还想起什么
If you think of anything else,
请马上来电
please, don't hesitate to call.
我没看出这些死者之间有联系
If these victims are connected, I can't see it.
关键一定是血
It's got to be about the blood.
血型也不同啊
Yeah, but even that's different.
加里是A+型  帕米是O-型
Gary was A-Positive, Pam was O-Neg.
最新死者
We just got the lab report
林恩・斯蒂文斯的实验室报告来了
back on the latest victim, Lynn Stevens.
她是AB-型
She was AB-Negative.
也许嫌犯是随机选择死者
Maybe these are just victims of opportunity.
不明嫌犯可能在
Well, it's possible the unsub
帕梅拉例行散步时绑架了她
abducted Pamela on one of her routine walks.
他可能用
He could have lured Gary
一笔有利可图的金钱交易引诱了加里
with the promise of a lucrative money deal.
我是艾米
Hi. I'm Aimee.
这地方不错
Nice place.
75块一小时
Ok, so it's going to be 75 for the hour.
超过一小时再议
Anything more than that we can discuss.
行吗
All right?
有地方让我换衣服吗
Someplace where I can get changed?
那边
There.
我不知道你喜欢什么体位
I don't know which positions you want me in,
不过我很全能
but I'm very flexible.
怎么了  小宝贝
What's up, baby girl?
我很担心里德
I'm worried about Reid.
我也是
I am, too.
你觉得他怎么样了
What do you think he's doing?
我觉得他在用霍奇给他的时间慢慢疗伤
I think he's taking the time that Hotch gave him.
我明白  他很难过  他应该难过的
I get it. He's sad. He should be sad.
但我很担心
But I'm so worried.
我爱的人受伤时
And when someone I love is hurting,
我也会跟着受伤  我太依赖别人了
it's like I hurt, too, which I know is super codependent,
但我就是这样的
but it's just how I roll,
我觉得自己应该做点什么
and I feel like I should be doing something,
虽说我不知道我能做什么
and I don't know what it is, but--
好了  慢慢说好吗  慢慢说
All right, slow down, all right? Just slow down.
你能给他打电话吗
Could you call him?
我打过了  但他现在还没准备好跟人交谈
I have. He's just not ready to talk to anybody right now.
我得听听他的声音  不然我没法工作
I need to hear his voice. It's impairing my ability to work.
我试试吧
Let me try something, all right?
谢谢
Thanks.
你好  我是斯宾塞・里德  请留言
Hello. This is Spencer Reid. Please leave a message.
里德  我是戴瑞  工作上有事请教你
Hey, Reid, it's Derek. Listen, I got a work question for you.
不明嫌犯放光了死者的血
The unsub's exsanguinating victims
还在他们临死前割掉了他们的眼睑
and removing their eyelids antemortem.
你有什么头绪吗  给我回电
Does that mean anything to you? Hit me back.
这是你要的信息
Here's the information you called about.
谢谢
Thank you.
失陪一下
Excuse me for a second.
怎么样  里德
What's up, Reid?
死者角膜和瞳孔有任何损伤吗
Have the cornea or pupils been harmed in any way?
没有  布莱克说看起来
No, no. Blake said it looked like
嫌犯用的是非常锋利的器械
a very sharp instrument was used.
要是他特别注意不损伤眼睛
If he's taking care not to damage the eyes,
那视线可能对他很重要
then line of sight is probably what's important to him.
这人希望死者看到他所做的事
So this guy wants them to see what he's doing.
里德  你怎么样
Hey, Reid. How are you?
我要挂了
I gotta go.
很抱歉
Sorry about that.
没关系
Not a problem.
死因肯定是失血致死
Cause of death would definitely be exsanguination.
不过毒性检测显示出极高含量的
But the tox screen showed high levels of--
以五倍的速度说一遍  乙二胺四乙酸
say this 5 times fast-- ethylene diamine tetra acetic.
EDTA  是一种阻凝剂
EDTA. It's an anti-coagulant.
多用于治疗心脏问题
Used mostly to treat heart conditions.
不明嫌犯可能是用它稀释血液
So the unsub probably used it to thin the blood.
我们发现的氯胺酮可能也起了同样的作用
The ketamine we found may have helped as well.
用在人身上会使血压升高
In humans, it tends to elevate blood pressure.
他就是借此让被害人昏迷的
Which is how he's sedating them.
如果他给被害人下药后
If he knew that he was giving these drugs to these victims
还把血喝了呢
and he ingested the blood?
就和给自己下药无异
He'd be dosing himself as well.
那就不是吸食人血了
Well, that rules out vampirism.
嫌犯可能在医学领域工作吗
Is there any chance this guy works in the medical field?
我看不像  伤口周围有一些试探伤
I doubt it. There are a few hesitation marks near the wound,
动脉的伤口周围有大面积瘀伤
and the hole in the artery shows a lot of bruising around it.
最多是个实习生
I'd say it's amateur at best.
好吧  这名嫌犯
All right, so we got an unsub
随机选择其被害人
who's picking his victims at random,
迷晕他们  再抽干他们的血
sedates them, then bleeds them dry.
如果不是把血喝了的话
If he's not drinking the blood,
他到底用血来做什么呢
what the hell is he doing with it?
等等
Wait...
别动
Shh, shh, shh. Be still.
你在做什么
What's--what-- what are you doing?
住手  住手
Wait--wait--aah!
我们查到了指纹
Well, we got a hit off the prints.
被害人名叫艾米・福特纳
The victim's name is Aimee Fortner.
距离他上次杀人仅过了一天
It's only been a day since his last kill.
这人都没有冷静周期
Well, this guy doesn't have a cool-down period.
尸体还没有僵硬
Rigor hasn't set in yet.
放在这应该也就一个小时
I'd say she was put here maybe an hour ago,
日出时分
just after sunrise.
他越来越肆无忌惮了
He's getting brazen.
这是他第一次白天弃尸
It's his first daytime disposal.
公园的这部分一般没人经过
Well, this part of the park's not very well traveled.
市政府一直想隔几年就整修一次
The city's been trying to renovate every couple of years,
不过你懂的  政治嘛
but you know--politics.
不明嫌犯对此地十分熟悉
So the unsub is familiar enough with the area
知道不会有人打扰他
to know nobody would disturb him.
万事屋  有什么需要效劳的
Office of omnipotence. How may I dazzle you?
加西亚  我需要最新被害人艾米・福特纳的信息
Garcia, I need information on the latest victim, Aimee Fortner.
提供信息是我最在行的  长官
Information is my favorite way to dazzle, sir.
包您满意
So sparkly.
有了 艾米・克里斯多・福特纳
Here we go Aimee Crystal Fortner.
来自圣克拉拉市
Originally from Santa Clara.
很漂亮
She was super pretty.
不做酒巴服务员后
When she wasn't bartending,
靠做模特维持生计
she supplemented her income by modeling.
模特
A model?
没错  她有个网站
Yes. And she's got a website
上面都是她的艺术照
full of very artistic pictures of herself.
这姑娘相当乐于炫耀她那天赐的身材
Girl was not afraid to flaunt what god gave her at all.
谢谢  加西亚
Uh-huh. Thanks, Garcia.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
里德告诉摩根被害人的视线
Reid told Morgan line of sight
对于不明嫌犯很重要
was important to the unsub.
我们该去看看其他犯罪现场
We should take a look at the other crime scenes.
我可能知道他用血做什么了
I might know what he's doing with the blood.
我们认为不明嫌犯是名白人男性
We believe that this unsub is a white male
20或30多岁
in his 20s or 30s,
他自认为是名画家或艺术家
and he thinks of himself as a painter or an artist.
弃尸地点透露了许多嫌犯的信息
The placement of the victims tells us a lot about who he is.
帕梅拉・赫德被发现的周围有一幅
Pamela hurd was found near a painting done by
鲜为人知的旧金山艺术家亨利・弗洛伊德的画作
little known San Francisco artist Henry Floyd.
加里・波特被放置于一幅街头涂鸦旁
Gary Porter was posed near a piece of graffiti art
作者是街头艺术家赛弗
by a street artist named Cypher,
目前此人正被警方通缉
who is currently wanted by the police.
第三名被害人  林恩・斯蒂文斯附近有幅壁画
And the third victim, Lynn Stevens, was found near a mural
是贫民区的青少年画的
painted by inner city youths.
最后  艾米・福特纳被弃尸在圣路加雕像旁
Finally, Aimee Fortner was placed near the statue of Saint Luke,
艺术家的保护神
patron saint of the artist.
这是起内心冲动引发的犯罪  并非偶然
This is a compulsion. It's not accidental.
他沉迷于艺术
He is obsessed with art.
那些艺术作品都被无视  忽略  抛弃了
All of the works of art are neglected, ignored, cast aside.
他认为自己也是如此
It's how he feels about himself.
我们相信这也是他
We believe it's also the reason that he's evolved in
切除被害人眼睑的原因
removing the victims' eyelids.
强迫他们看他所看
He's forcing them to see what he sees.
这些谋杀与性欲无关
There's no sexual component with these murders,
因为血液本身及其用途就是他
but that's because the blood and the use of the blood
释放性欲的方式
is his sexual release.
等等
So, wait.
他用那些血做了什么
What--what is he doing with the blood?
他太沉溺于艺术
Because he's so obsessed with art,
我们认为他用血液作画
we believe he's painting with it.
他频频杀人
He has a quick kill pace.
更多的血液意味着更多的画作
More blood means more paint.
而他作的画越多
The more paintings he does,
有人认出他的作品的概率就越大
the greater the chance someone will recognize his work.
我们认为  为了得到认同
We think that because of his need for acceptance,
他可能会试着卖出自己的作品
he may be trying to sell the paintings.
所以请密切关注可能出售
So focus your canvassing on places
这种边缘作品的地方
that might sell this kind of fringe art.
怎么了  小鬼
What's up, kid?
如果事关艺术
If it is about the art,
那么很明显抛尸地点分散在
then it's clear the disposal sites are scattered
教会区周围
around the Mission District area.
等等  你怎么知道
Wait a minute. How did you know--
我让安德森带了些卷宗给我
I had Anderson bring over some of the files.
好  好  等一下  我把加西亚接进来
All right. All right, hold on a second. Let me patch in Garcia.
他说了什么  他还好吗
What have you heard? Is he ok?
别急  别急
Slow down. Slow down.
里德
Reid.
加西亚  你应该列出
Garcia, you should pull a list
旧金山所有的画廊
of all the art galleries in San Francisco.
里德  我刚刚
Reid, I was just--
你怎么样
How are you?
好些了
Better.
多谢关心
Thanks for asking.
另外谢谢你的坚果篮
And thanks for the baskets.
坚果富含镁元素  可以促进分泌
You know, nuts have magnesium, which helps produce--
血清素  我知道
Serotonin. Yeah. I know.
好了  画廊  我搜到了很多
Ok, galleries. I got a lot.
注意教会区的画廊
Focus on the Mission District.
好歹开口了
I guess that's better than nothing.
对  我也这么想
It is. I will take it.
还是有好些画廊  不过查起来容易多了
Ok, there's still a few galleries, but it's more manageable.
我把地址发到你手机上了
I am sending the addresses to your mobile.
收到了  谢了  加西亚
I got it. Thanks, Garcia.
不客气
Yeah.
这是赫尔曼的原作
It's an original Hellman.
他在临终前画下这幅作品
He painted it while literally on his deathbed.
10,000.
-麦迪森  -什么
- Madison. - Yeah?
他又来了
He's back.
博物馆已经准备好出价了
The museum is ready to make me an offer.
很好
Perfect.
如果你愿意的话  我可以让他离开
If you want, I can tell him to leave.
不用了  没事
No, it's ok.
赖利女士
Mrs. Riley.
我想这次你会对我的作品更满意的
I think you'll be much more pleased with my piece this time.
我已经说过了
Yeah, um, like I told you the last time,
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
为什么呢
Why not?
因为这不是我们
Well, because this type of art
想要的艺术风格
is just not what we're looking for.
那你们想要什么样的呢
Well, what is it you are looking for?
看得出来你有所进步
Look, I can see that you're getting better.
我能说的是  这幅画有点简略过头了
All I can tell you is it's a little simplistic.
所有伟大的艺术家都会
Look, every good artist leaves
在某种程度上将自己融入画作
a piece of himself on the canvas.
你得找出
You have to find that one thing
能让你脱颖而出的东西
that's going to set you apart from the rest of the crowd.
我用血画的
I used blood.
我指的不是特殊的材料
An unusual medium is not what I'm talking about.
今天的一切都毫无道理
The world today doesn't make sense.
我为何还要画出有意义的作品呢
Why should I paint pictures that do?
毕加索
Picasso.
真不错
I'm impressed.
如果我找到了自己的特色
If I find my signature,
你会考虑在画廊收录我的作品吗
you'll consider me for the gallery?
不无可能
Anything's possible.
我知道了
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
需要我帮忙吗
Can I help you?
我们是联调局的
We're from the FBI.
你是这里的老板吗
You the owner?
是的  我叫特雷
Yeah. Name's Tre.
你有没有展出以血液为颜料的作品
Do you have any art on display where blood is used as a medium?
没有
No.
没有  但几天前有个人过来
No, but there was a guy in here a couple days ago
想要卖这样的作品
who tried to sell me a piece like that.
这不太对我的胃口
It wasn't exactly my taste,
不过正好有个客户在这里
but a customer of mine happened to be in here,
一看到就爱上了那幅画  当时就买下来了
saw it, fell in love with it, bought it on sight.
那会是你们要找的人吗
You think that could that be your guy?
你这里不会正好有监控摄像头吧
You wouldn't happen to have any security cameras in here, would you?
没有
No.
如果你找到他的名字  请告诉我们
We need the customer's name if you've got it.
好
Yeah.
我完全看不懂这些东西
I never quite understood these things.
感觉作者在作画时处于癫狂状态
It all looks like the guy had a seizure while painting it.
作者是埃米尔・哈特福德
It's Emile Hartford.
是20世纪初的作品
It's early 20th century.
他女儿八岁时夭折
His daughter died when she was 8.
他说每当作画时  就能看见女儿
He said every time he painted, he'd be able to see her.
我不知道这画上能看出什么来
Don't know how you see anything in there.
难怪他们说  艺术是给有缘人看的
I guess that's why they say art is in the eye of the beholder.
是啊
Yeah.
还有样东西也需要有缘人
You know what else is in the eye of the beholder?
记得我上周说的57年雪弗兰吗
'57 Chevy I told you about last week?
就在今早  砰  它寿终正寝
This morning, bam, it won't start.
现在修理师就是它的有缘人
Now it's in the eye of my mechanic.
你是要我求你呢
Come on, man, are you gonna make me ask
还是心甘情愿把我当朋友  送我回家
or are you gonna be a friend and offer me a ride home?
我们算朋友
We're friends.
都共事两年了  应该算吧
Worked together for two years now. I'd hope so.
要我开车送你吗  保罗
You need a ride, Paul?
我还以为你不会问呢
Thought you'd never ask.
嫌犯把作品卖到这个地方
The unsub sold his painting to this place?
这里让我想起80年代
It reminds me of the eighties.
干嘛
What?
我会感兴趣吗
Do I even want to know?
或许吧
Probably.
欢迎光临  我是安德雷
Welcome. My name is Andre.
首先  请你们填一份弃权单
Before we start, I'll need you to fill out a small waiver.
不不  我们不是一对
No, no, no. We're not a couple.
不管什么关系  我们都竭诚为您服务
That's ok. We cater to all kinds of relationships.
其实我们是联调局的
Well, uh, our relationship is with the FBI.
哎呀
Oh.
我开的店没有问题
I run a clean establishment here.
清白  合法  成人娱乐
Clean, legal, adult fun.
冷静  我们只是来找一幅你最近买的画
Calm down. We're just looking for a painting you bought recently.
请你们说清楚点
You're gonna have to be a bit more specific.
我可是黑暗堕落艺术的鉴赏行家
I'm a connoisseur of the dark and depraved arts.
我买的画多了去了
I purchase a lot of paintings.
这幅画是你在几天前买的
Well, you bought this one a couple of days ago.
它用鲜血作成
It's made with blood.
是人血
Human blood.
我说过  我买的画太多
Like I said, I buy a lot of paintings.
我都记不清了
I don't remember them all.
是吗  不过我记得
Oh, really? Because last I checked,
私藏证据会让你成为共犯
withholding evidence would make you an accomplice.
我们只是想看看这幅画
We just want to see the painting.
确认一下  它是否出自我们要找的人之手
Just want to see if it's from the guy we're looking for.
现在想起来了吗
Remembering now?
好像想起来了
Possibly.
要看那幅画  你们得跟我去"打屁屁"房间
For that piece, you'll have to follow me to the spanking room.
我买它时可没想到
I may have bought it, but I didn't realize
它会成为什么证据
it was evidence of any sort.
这就是你们找的画吗
Is that that you're looking for?
她那饱受折磨的眼神让我眼前一亮
The tortured look in her eyes is what first drew me to it.
那人要价1500
The guy was asking 1,500 for it.
我还价到250  现金支付
I got him to take 250, cash.
那是第一位被害人  帕梅拉・赫德
That's our first victim, Pamela Hurd.
这绝对是嫌犯画的
It's definitely from our guy.
我们要带走这幅画
Yeah, we're gonna need to take this.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
什么...
What...
发生了什么事
What's going on?
怎么
What--
别这样  求你了
No, please don't.
为什么
Why?
我别无选择
It's the only way.
对不起
Sorry.
你疯了
You're insane.
艺术家不都是疯子吗
I guess every artist is a little crazy.
别这样  我们是朋友
No, come on man, we're friends.
正因如此
Exactly.
这就是我画中所缺失的
It's what I've been missing.
私人元素
Something personal.
你别动
I need you to hold still.
别动
Hold still.
Hold still...
不要动
Hold still!
救命啊
Help!
不
No! Aah!
No!
不要
No...No!
现在我们有了嫌犯的作品
Well, we now have a piece of his art,
但依然没有能够查出他身份的线索
but we still don't have anything to identify the unsub.
实验室拿到样本
The lab's got a sample,
但那八成是帕梅拉・赫德的血
but it's probably Pamela Hurd's blood.
安德雷大师说他是一个普通白人
Master Andre said he was an average white guy
二三十岁
in his late 20s to early 30s.
画廊老板也这么说  他署了名
Same thing the gallery owner said. He signed it.
看起来像是以字母B开头或结尾的名字
Yeah, it looks like a "B" something or something "B".
我叫加西亚整理一份名字里
I'm going to have Garcia compile a list of artists
带字母B的艺术家的名单
with the letter "B" somewhere in their name.
虽然线索很少  但总算没一无所获
It's not much, but it's something.
实验室报告出来了
We got the report back from the lab.
从画作上无法提取DNA
They couldn't extract any DNA from the painting.
他们说上面的血只有红细胞
They said something about there only being red blood cells.
看来他提取了白细胞
Hmm. He removed the white blood cells.
血浆
Plasma.
他要血浆做什么
Why would he take the plasma?
增加浓度  更好作画
It would make it thicker. Easier to use as a paint.
要怎样的设备才能提取
What type of equipment would it take to do that?
只需几百美元就能网购
You can easily buy a centrifuge online these days
一个离心分离器
for a couple hundred bucks.
他从血液里提取血浆
What other reasons would he
还有其他可能的原因吗
have for separating the plasma from the blood?
是个人习惯
It's a habit.
-里德  -斯宾塞
- Reid. - Spence.
我没想到你这么快就回来了
I didn't expect you back this soon.
你确定准备好了吗
You sure you're ready?
没有  我只是对案件有些想法
No, but I think I figured something out.
赖利女士在哪
Where's Mrs. Riley?
请你离开
You need to leave.
不要紧  艾伦  我来处理
It's ok, Alan, I'll handle it.
我照你说的做了
I did what you said.
这是我的朋友  保罗
This is my friend, Paul.
我甚至用了些自己的血
I even used some of my own blood.
我说的不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
但你说过如果我加入私人元素
But you said if I made it more personal,
就可以为画廊所用
you'd use me in your gallery.
我一直对你很客气  不断地鼓励你
Look, I've been trying to be nice and give you some encouragement,
但我现在发现这样完全帮不了你
but I can see now that that's really not gonna help you.
所以我就直言不讳了
So I think I just have to be blunt.
你的作品不怎么样
It's not good.
但是...
But...
这幅
This is--
这幅是抽象派作品
This is abstract.
我知道抽象派的意思
I understand the concept,
但在画布上随便洒点颜料
but splashing something onto a canvas,
不能称为艺术
that doesn't make it art.
天赋是与生俱来的  不是每人都能拥有
Some people have it, some people don't.
你不知道你自己在说些什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
可能是  但我还是不会买下这幅画
Maybe not, but that still doesn't mean that I'm gonna buy this.
但你说过
But you said--
真不知道要怎么说你才明白
Look, I don't know how to explain this to you any better.
梦想和才华是有差别的
There is a difference between a dream and a talent.
抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
如果有人可以让你...
If there's someone that you--
他是血友病患者
He's a hemophiliac.
所以他才对血如此着迷
That would explain his obsession with blood.
他一流血就会害怕死亡
He can't bleed without a fear of dying.
正因如此  他才在作画以前先把血浆
It's also why he would separate the plasma from the blood
从血液里分离出来
before painting with it.
这是一种古老的疗法
It's an antiquated treatment,
血友病患者在自己的伤口注射血浆
but some hemophiliacs can inject plasma into their wounds,
加强在他们体内
kick-starting the clotting
已经失效的血凝能力
process that's ineffective in their own systems.
说吧
Talk about it.
美妞  我需要一份旧金山的血友病患者名单
Hey, girlie, I need a list of hemophiliacs in San Francisco.
撒的网可真大啊
Vague. So vague. Ok.
加西亚  他的执念非常强烈
Garcia, for his obsession to be this profound,
所以他很可能病得很重
he most likely has the more severe version of the disease.
B型血友病[克里斯马斯病]
It's type B Christmas disease.
里德  你平安无事  我很开心
Reid, I'm happy to hear you made it safe and sound.
谢谢关心  加西亚
Thank you, Garcia.
B型血友病  听起来很惨啊
Ok, Christmas disease. It does not sound very jolly.
此病是以第一个确诊病人
It was named after the first known case,
史蒂芬・克里斯马斯命名的
Stephen Christmas.
我找到15个患此病的人
All right, I got 15 people who have trouble clotting.
他的生活应该与艺术有关
He wouldn't stray too far from the art world.
他应该从事
Most likely works in and
与艺术相关的工作  但他本人并非艺术家
around the art community, but not as an artist.
而且他很孤僻  查查从事无需和外界
And he's a loner. So look for people with jobs
打交道的工作的人
where they don't interact with the public.
现在范围缩小到三人
Yeah. Yeah. I got 3.
当地超市的采购部门职员  艺术博客作家
Stock boy at a local supermarket, an art blogger,
和一个托管人
and a custodian.
几名被害人的血型均不相同
The victims have different blood types.
如果他要注射提取出的血浆
If he's taking the plasma out of the blood,
那他应该是个全适受血者
he must be a universal recipient.
他们中有人是AB型RH阳性血吗
Any of them with AB-positive blood?
这条很具体  我搜搜看
Specificity. I dig it.
再结合一下名字里带字母B的...
Ok, if I factor in those "B" names I was working on...
揭开真面目咯
And bingo is his name-o.
他叫布莱恩・休斯
Actually, his name is Bryan Hughes.
是一名AB阳性血友病患者
He is an AB-positive hemophiliac
在海湾区艺术馆当守卫
who works as a janitor at the Bay Area Museum of Art,
不劳你们多问
and before you ask, yes,
他的地址已发到你们手机上
his address has been sent to your phones.
你最棒了  宝贝
You're the best, baby girl.
戴夫  你和布莱克去艺术馆
Dave, you and Blake take the museum.
其余人去他的住处
The rest of us will take the residence.
我没事
I'm ok.
那就好  还是很高兴看到你
Yeah. But it's good to see you.
如果你还没休整好  真的不必着急回来
You really don't need to be here if you're not ready.
这要花些时间
This is going to take time.
多长时间
How much time?
很难说
It's hard to say.
我们都在你身边
But we're all here for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
有何发现  美女
Hey, what you got, mama?
发现有关这个布莱恩・休斯的一条重大信息
A compelling piece of information about this Bryan Hughes.
第一起凶案发生的三周前
3 weeks before the first murder,
他出了一场车祸
he was involved in a car accident.
受伤了吗
Was he injured?
没有  如果你看到我正看的这些图
Uh, no. And if you were looking at the pictures I am
一定会觉得这是个奇迹
you would say that is a miracle.
他可能由此产生了自己刀枪不入的想法
It may have given him the impression he couldn't be hurt.
另一名司机受伤了  流血过多致死
The other driver was hurt. She bled to death.
休斯报了警
Hughes called 911,
但没有提及还有另一名司机
failed to mention there was another driver involved.
急救人员赶到时  她已身亡
By the time emergency crews got there, she had already died.
谢谢  加西亚
Thanks, Garcia.
眼看着另一个女人流血致死
Watching the other woman bleed to death
这一定就是导火索
must have been the trigger.
有什么发现  帅哥
Hey, what you got, pretty boy?
休斯可能已经有了下一个作案目标
I think Hughes may have his next victim.
一个叫艾伦・阿奇尔的刚刚来报案说他的老板不见了
An Alan Archer just came in and reported his boss missing.
麦迪森・赖利在教会区有一间画廊
Madison Riley owns an art gallery in the Mission District.
据称现场有血迹和打斗痕迹
Said there was blood, signs of a struggle.
这次休斯甚至在墙上留了一副自己的画作
Hughes even left a painting of his on the wall this time.
同样的签名  而且绝对是用血画的
It's the same signature and it's definitely made of blood,
这让我想起梅芙的跟踪狂
which got me thinking about Maeve's stalker.
如果这家伙是一个寻求认同的扭曲的艺术家
If this guy's a tortured artist searching for approval,
那么他应该认为只有一种方法能得到认同
in his mind there may be only one way to get it.
自杀
Suicide.
多谢  里德
Thanks, Reid.
我全身心地投入这些画作
I put my heart and my soul into those paintings.
你将亲眼见证我卓越的创作能力
You're going to get a first-hand look at what I'm capable of creating.
布莱恩・休斯  联邦调查局
Bryan Hughes, FBI.
不  我必须让她看到
No! I have to make her see.
把刀放下
Put down the knife.
布莱恩  我明白
Bryan, I understand.
不  你不明白
No, you don't.
你怎么可能明白
How could you possibly understand?
因为我看过你的大作
Because I've seen your work.
我知道可能你现在还无人赏识
And I know you may not be appreciated now,
但我向你保证  如果你放下刀
but I promise you, if you put down the knife,
我会保证让世人欣赏到你的艺术
I will make sure that people see your art,
而且没人能够忽视
and no one will be able to ignore it.
这就是我想要的  那是我应得的
It's all I want. I deserve that.
那就把刀放下  我们把这事解决
Then put down the knife, and let's figure this out.
你知道梵高死前卖了多少幅画吗
You know how many paintings Van Gogh sold before he died?
布莱恩  别犯傻
Bryan, don't do it.
两幅
Two.
他卖了两幅
He sold two.
别逼我们出手
Don't make us do this.
我必须让你看到我
I gotta make you see me.
让急救人员到楼上来
Get the EMTs upstairs.
这里还有一具尸体
We've got another body over here.
我猜五篮
Well, I counted 5 baskets.
七篮  但我觉得隔壁的卡瓦诺小姐
7, but I think Ms. Cavanaugh next door
可能拿了几个走
may have taken a couple.
真的很抱歉  如果我之前有点...
I'm really sorry if I've been kind of...
斯宾塞  不用
Spence. You don't...
孩子
Kid.
我找你  不是为了让你到现场来帮忙
I didn't mean for you to come all the way out there.
我知道
I know.
如果你有任何需要
Listen, if you need anything at all,
开口就好
you just have to ask.
事实上  如果你们不介意的话
Actually, if you guys don't mind,
我想请你们帮个忙
I could use some help with something.
说
Name it.
有时最难的并非放下过去
"Sometimes the hardest part isn't letting go,
而是学会重新开始
but rather, learning to start over."
作家妮可・索邦
Nicole Sobon.